YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series III. Public Advocacy
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. PUBLIC ADVOCACY
  - Subseries A. General
    - General and History
      - 50th Anniversary of Public Affairs Program (celebrated jointly with National Council of Jewish Women), 1961-62
        - Planning (Box 389, Folder 4)
        - Press releases and news clippings (Box 389, Folder 5)
        - Program and speeches (Box 389, Folder 6)
        - National Council of Jewish Women (Box 389, Folder 7)
        - Local Associations (Box 389, Folder 8)
      - National Forum on Women: Strategies for the Decade (part of International Women's Year), 18 Nov 1975 (Box 389, Folder 9)
    - Office/Staff
      - Legislative Service, 1920-28 (Box 389, Folder 10)
      - Public Affairs/Public Policy
        - 1928-69 (Box 389, Folder 11-17)
        - 1970-92, n.d. (Box 390, Folder 1)
      - Advocacy and Research Division
        - General, 1994-2000, n.d. (Box 390, Folder 2-6)
        - Public Policy text for YW Link, 1997 (Box 390, Folder 7)
        - Reference book, 1997 (Box 390, Folder 8-9)
      - Child Care Services and Advocacy
        - General, 1994-2000, n.d. (Box 391, Folder 1)
        - Clippings, 1994, 1997 (Box 391, Folder 2)
        - Child Care Network, 1995-2001 (Box 391, Folder 3)
        - Child Care Advisory Panel, 1998-2001, n.d. (Box 391, Folder 4)
        - Child Care Affinity Group, 2000 (Box 391, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, 1995-2001, n.d. (Box 391, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence to legislators from Member Associations, 1998 (Box 391, Folder 7)
        - Lobbying and testimony, 1994-99, n.d. (Box 391, Folder 8)
    - Controversy
      - General, 1940-97 (Box 391, Folder 9)
      - Public Affairs Issues, 1920-76 (Box 391, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence re relations with Community Chests and Councils, 1947-48 (Box 391, Folder 11)
      - Seattle, Washington, and Eunice P. Clise, 1946-48 (Box 391, Folder 12)
      - Strategies of other organizations, 1948-70 (Box 391, Folder 13)
    - Committees and Subcommittees
      - Legislative Committee
        - 1920-26 (Box 391, Folder 14-16)
        - 1927-28 (Box 392, Folder 1-3)
      - Council on International Peace/International Education [aka Peace Council], 1924-28 (Box 392, Folder 4-5)
      - Public Affairs Committee
        - General, 1941-73 (Box 392, Folder 6)
        - Appointments, 1940-50 (Box 392, Folder 7-8)
        - Rosters, 1961-72 (Box 392, Folder 9)
        - Minutes and reports
          - 1930-40 (Box 392, Folder 10-18)
          - 1941-68 (Box 393, Folder 1-12)
          - 1969 (Box 394, Folder 1)
        - State members
          - Rosters, 1935-39 (Box 394, Folder 2)
          - Correspondence, 1930-49 (Box 394, Folder 3-6)
        - Subcommittees
          - Civil Liberties Group/Sub-committee, 1939-49 (Box 394, Folder 7)
          - Economic Section/Subcommittee, 1933-41, 1947 (Box 394, Folder 8)
          - International Education/International
            - General, 1936-49 (Box 394, Folder 9-10)
            - Minutes, 1929-50 (Box 394, Folder 11-15)
          - Race Relations
            - 1933-41 (Box 394, Folder 16-17)
            - 1942-50 (Box 395, Folder 1-5)
          - Social Responsibility (Local Public Affairs)
            - General, 1940-44 (Box 395, Folder 6-7)
            - Minutes, 1940-44 (Box 395, Folder 8)
          - Social Security, 1936-37 (Box 395, Folder 9)
          - Washington, DC segment of Public Affairs Committee, 1963-71 (Box 395, Folder 10)
      - Ad-hoc Group on Public Policy, 1969 (Box 395, Folder 11)
      - Ad-hoc Committee on New Focus for Public Affairs Program, 1969-70 (Box 395, Folder 12)
      - Public Policy Committee, 1987-97 (Box 395, Folder 13-25)
      - Public Policy and Advocacy Committee, 1998 (Box 396, Folder 1-2)
    - Mailings ["Circular Letters"]
      - Legislative Committee, 1922-28 (Box 396, Folder 3-6)
      - Public Affairs Committee
        - 1928-43 (Box 396, Folder 7-16)
        - 1944-50 (Box 397, Folder 1-7)
      - Public Policy
        - General, 1989, 1997 (Box 397, Folder 8)
        - Child Care, Dec 1994-2000 (Box 397, Folder 9-10)
    - Programs and Projects
      - Child Care
        - Child Care Marketing Campaign (Box 397, Folder 11)
        - Child Care Project: funding proposals, 1995-96 (Box 397, Folder 12)
        - Family Communications, Inc., anti-bias pilot project, 1998 (Box 397, Folder 13)
        - Goizueta Foundation grants, 1999-2002 (Box 397, Folder 14)
        - Lifetime Television "Caring for Kids" Project, 1999 (Box 398, Folder 1)
        - "Same and Different" anti-bias pilot program, 1995 (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - 21st Century Community Learning Center grants, 1999 (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - Stand for Children Day 2000 Event Planning Kit (Box 398, Folder 4)
      - Mothers' Center Pilot Project, 1987-91 (Box 398, Folder 5)
      - Political Participation/Empowerment
        - YWCA/National Women's Education Fund Model Political Campaign Seminars, 1985-86 (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - Election Year '88 Voter Participation Project, 1988 (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - 1992 Voter Participation Project (Box 398, Folder 8)
        - Institute for Public Leadership
          - General, 1985-90, n.d. (Box 398, Folder 9)
          - Local Sponsor Kit, n.d. (Box 398, Folder 10)
          - Women's Political Empowerment Program
            - Overview, 1997-98, 2001 (Box 398, Folder 11-12)
            - "Campaign Sourcebook," Jan 1995 (Box 398, Folder 13)
            - "Making Your Workshop a Winner: A Step-by-step Guide to Planning and Marketing Your IPL Workshop," 1995 (Box 398, Folder 14)
            - Voter registration and education activities at member associations, 1996 (Box 398, Folder 15-16)
            - Women Empowered to Shape Public Policy Project
              - Proposal to Ford Foundation, 1996 (Box 399, Folder 1)
              - Final Report to Ford Foundation, 1998 (Box 399, Folder 2)
            - Campaign Skills Workshop
              - Campaign Sourcebook, 1997, 1998, 2002 (Box 399, Folder 3-5)
              - Step-by-Step Planning and Marketing Guide (Box 399, Folder 6)
              - Trainers' Manual (Box 399, Folder 7)
            - EmPowerNet News, 2000 (Box 400, Folder 1)
            - "I Speak Out" advocacy training program
              - General, 1997, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 2)
              - Workshops
                - Cast packet, May 1997 (Box 400, Folder 3)
                - Coordinators Sourcebook, 1997 (Box 400, Folder 4)
                - Baton Rouge, Louisiana, May 1997 (Box 400, Folder 5)
                - Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, Mar 1997 (Box 400, Folder 6)
                - Salem, Oregon, Mar 1997 (Box 400, Folder 7)
                - Individuals' evaluations, 1997 (Box 400, Folder 8-9)
                - YWCA of Western New York: Advocacy Sourcebook, Child Care Packet Apr 2000 (Box 400, Folder 10)
              - "Advocacy Sourcebook," Nov 1999, 2000 (Box 400, Folder 11)
              - "Step-by-Step Planning and Marketing Guide," Jul 1999 (Box 400, Folder 12)
              - Follow-up questionnaires, 1998 (Box 400, Folder 13)
            - "I Vote" voter participation project
              - General, 1996 (Box 400, Folder 14)
              - Orientation, Sep 1996 (Box 400, Folder 15)
              - Reports from participating YWCAs, 1996 (Box 401, Folder 1)
            - Voter Education Discussion Papers (Box 401, Folder 2)
            - Voter Education reference materials, circa 1996 (Box 401, Folder 3)
        - Women's Vote Project '96: The Deciding Vote
          - General, 1995-96, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 4)
          - Affiliate sites, 1996 (Box 401, Folder 5)
          - Committees
            - Administrative, 1995-96 (Box 401, Folder 6)
            - Grassroots, 1996 (Box 401, Folder 7)
          - Consultants, 1996-97 (Box 401, Folder 8)
          - Council of Presidents of National Women's Organizations, 1996 (Box 401, Folder 9)
          - Financial
            - General, 1995-97, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 10)
            - Reports and tax forms, 1995-97, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 11)
            - Final reports to funders, 1997 (Box 401, Folder 12)
          - Grant applications, 1996 (Box 401, Folder 13)
          - HumanSERVE: correspondence and reference materials, 1995-96 (Box 401, Folder 14)
          - Local events, 1995-96 (Box 401, Folder 15)
          - State Coordinators
            - General, 1996 (Box 401, Folder 16)
            - Training, Jul 1996 (Box 402, Folder 1)
          - Reference materials (Box 402, Folder 2-3)
        - YWCA Campaign 2000…We Vote and Our Voices are Heard (Box 402, Folder 4)
      - Violence Prevention
        - Week Without Violence, 1995
          - General (Box 402, Folder 5)
          - Media Kit (Box 402, Folder 6)
          - Organizers Kit (Box 402, Folder 7)
          - Follow up: Confronting Violence in our Communities (Box 402, Folder 8)
        - Week Without Violence, 1996
          - General (Box 402, Folder 9)
          - Organizers Kit (Box 402, Folder 10)
          - Alabama: Birmingham (Box 402, Folder 11)
          - California
            - Los Angeles (Box 402, Folder 12)
            - Mid-peninsula/Palo Alto (Box 402, Folder 13)
            - Orange, North (Box 403, Folder 1)
            - Orange, South (Box 403, Folder 2)
            - San Francisco (Box 403, Folder 3-4)
            - Santa Monica (Box 403, Folder 5)
            - Watsonville (Box 403, Folder 6)
            - Other YWCA events (Box 403, Folder 7)
          - Colorado: Boulder (Box 403, Folder 8)
          - Connecticut
            - Darien-Norwalk (Box 403, Folder 9)
            - Greenwich (Box 403, Folder 10)
            - Hartford (Box 403, Folder 11)
            - Meriden (Box 403, Folder 12)
          - District of Columbia (Box 403, Folder 13)
          - Florida
            - Jacksonville (Box 403, Folder 14)
            - Palm Beach County (Box 403, Folder 15)
          - Georgia
            - Central Savannah River Area (Box 403, Folder 16)
            - Cobb County (Box 403, Folder 17)
          - Hawaii
            - Hawaii Island (Box 403, Folder 18)
            - Kauai County (Box 403, Folder 19)
          - Idaho: Southeastern (Box 403, Folder 20)
          - Illinois
            - Aurora (Box 403, Folder 21)
            - Chicago (Box 403, Folder 22)
            - Freeport (Box 403, Folder 23)
            - McLean County (Box 403, Folder 24)
            - Pekin (Box 403, Folder 25)
            - Sauk Valley (Box 403, Folder 26)
          - Indiana
            - Elkhart County (Box 403, Folder 27)
            - Fort Wayne (Box 403, Folder 28)
            - Gary (Box 403, Folder 29)
            - Lafayette (Box 403, Folder 30)
            - St. Joseph County (Box 403, Folder 31)
          - Iowa
            - Ames-Iowa State University (Box 403, Folder 32)
            - Des Moines (Box 403, Folder 33)
            - Washington (Box 403, Folder 34)
          - Kansas
            - Salina (Box 403, Folder 35)
            - Topeka (Box 403, Folder 36)
            - Wichita (Box 403, Folder 37)
          - Louisiana
            - Baton Rouge (Box 403, Folder 38)
            - New Orleans (Box 404, Folder 1)
            - Northwest Louisiana (Shreveport) (Box 404, Folder 2)
          - Massachusetts
            - Boston (Box 404, Folder 3)
            - Cambridge (Box 404, Folder 4)
            - Central Massachusetts (Box 404, Folder 5)
            - Lawrence (Box 404, Folder 6)
            - Southeastern Massachusetts (Box 404, Folder 7)
          - Maryland: Morgan State University (Box 404, Folder 8)
          - Maine
            - Bangor-Brewer (Box 404, Folder 9)
            - Lewiston-Auburn (Box 404, Folder 10)
            - Mount Desert Island (Box 404, Folder 11)
            - Portland (Box 404, Folder 12)
          - Michigan
            - Bay County (Box 404, Folder 13)
            - Lansing (Box 404, Folder 14)
          - Missouri: Kansas City (Box 404, Folder 15)
          - Montana
            - Billings (Box 404, Folder 16)
            - Missoula (Box 404, Folder 17)
          - Nebraska
            - Adams County (Box 404, Folder 18)
            - Omaha (Box 404, Folder 19)
          - New Jersey
            - Bergen County (Box 404, Folder 20)
            - Eastern Union County (Box 404, Folder 21)
            - Montclair-North Essex (Box 404, Folder 22)
            - Plainfield/North Plainfield (Box 404, Folder 23)
            - Princeton (Box 404, Folder 24)
          - North Carolina
            - Asheville (Box 404, Folder 25)
            - Central Carolinas (Box 404, Folder 26)
            - Greensboro (Box 404, Folder 27)
            - High Point (Box 404, Folder 28)
            - Rocky Mount (Box 404, Folder 29)
            - Wilmington (Box 404, Folder 30)
            - Winston-Salem/Forsyth County (Box 404, Folder 31)
          - North Dakota: Fargo/Moorhead (Box 404, Folder 32)
          - South Carolina: Upper Lowlands (Box 404, Folder 33)
          - Utah: Salt Lake City
            - 1-3 of 5 (Box 404, Folder 34-36)
            - 4-5 of 5 (Box 405, Folder 1-2)
        - Week Without Violence, 1997
          - General (Box 405, Folder 3)
          - Organizers Kit (Box 405, Folder 4)
          - Executive report (Box 405, Folder 5)
        - Week Without Violence, 1998-2000, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 6-7)
    - Publications
      - Miscellaneous, 1958-59, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 8)
      - Backgrounds and Foregrounds in the National Public Affairs Program for the Foreign Born by Mabel Brown Ellis, 1938 (Box 405, Folder 9)
      - Hunger: An Action Guide, 1969 (Box 405, Folder 9a)
      - Implementing the Nestle Resolution: A Program Paper, 1980 (Box 405, Folder 10)
      - Interpreting International Relations and the YWCA, 1930 (Box 405, Folder 10a)
      - Locally Speaking-being an exchange of program ideas, methods and techniques in the real of Public Affairs, 1941 (Box 405, Folder 11)
      - The Past is Prelude: Fifty Years of Social Action in the YWCA by Elsie D. Harper, 1963 (Box 405, Folder 12)
      - A Primer on Economics by Elsie D. Harper, 1935 (Box 405, Folder 13)
      - A Primer of Public Affairs by Margaret Hiller, 1932 (Box 405, Folder 14)
      - Program Help on International Relationships, Program series no. 32, 1926 (Box 405, Folder 15)
      - Public Affairs and the YWCA, 1931, 1933 revised (Box 405, Folder 16)
      - The Public Affairs Committee by Elsie D. Harper, 1943 (Box 406, Folder 1-2)
      - Public Affairs in the YWCA, 1957 (Box 406, Folder 3)
      - "Reproductive Choice Action Packet," 1995 (Box 406, Folder 4)
      - Toward International Organization by Margaret E. Burton and "Program Suggestions for the Use of Toward International Organization" by Margaret Hiller, 1940 (Box 406, Folder 5)
      - Toward World Government by Henrietta Roelofs, 1942 (Box 406, Folder 6)
      - The Traffic in Arms by Myra A. Smith, 1934 (Box 406, Folder 7)
      - Uncle Sam at Geneva: The United States and the League of Nations, Programs for Clubs and Committees by Margaret Hiller, 1938 (Box 406, Folder 8)
      - What About the YWCA and Labor? by Dorothy Hubbard Bishop, 1946 (Box 406, Folder 9)
      - "What Every YWCA Should Know About Gun Abuse: A Program Paper," Public Policy Center, May 1974 (Box 406, Folder 9a)
      - The World and All: Programs about the League of Nations and the International Labour Organisation for use by YWCA groups in various countries by Margaret Hiller, 1938 (Box 406, Folder 10)
      - "Your Vote is Your Voice: A Kit for Voter Registration, Education and Turnout Programs," 1983 (Box 406, Folder 11)
      - The Y's Word: An All-Association Project, 1931 (Box 406, Folder 12)
      - YWCA Cares for Children: A Guidebook for YWCA Child Care Centers, 1998 (Box 406, Folder 13-16)
      - Serials
        - Public Affairs Newsletter
          - 1946-49 (Box 406, Folder 17-20)
          - 1956-80 (Box 407, Folder 1-9)
        - Public Affairs News Service
          - Series 1-2, 1936-Aug 1938 (Box 407, Folder 10-13)
          - Series 3-8, Oct 1938-May 1944 (Box 408, Folder 1-10)
          - Series 9-Volume 14, Oct 1944-51 (Box 409, Folder 1-7)
        - Public Affairs Size 16, parts 1-3 by Margaret Hiller, 1939-40 (Box 409, Folder 8-9)
        - Public Policy Bulletin
          - 1981-82 (Box 409, Folder 10)
          - 1983-92 (Box 410, Folder 1-9)
          - 1995-2000 (Box 411, Folder 1-5)
        - Violence Against Women Network Newsletter, 1999-2000 (Box 411, Folder 6)
        - Womans Press columns, "The Capital Letter" and "Public Affairs," 1939-49 (Box 411, Folder 7-8)
        - YWCA Cares for Children: A Newsletter for YWCA Child Care Advocates, 1997-2001 (Box 411, Folder 9-10)
    - Reports
      - Law Reporting Service/Legislative Service, 1920-28 (Box 411, Folder 11-12)
      - Peace Council [Council on International Peace], 1924-25 (Box 411, Folder 13)
      - Public Affairs Committee/Program
        - 1929-45 (Box 411, Folder 14-16)
        - 1946-88 (Box 412, Folder 1-4)
      - State Members, 1933-41 (Box 412, Folder 5)
    - Surveys
      - Anti-Violence Programs of the YWCA, 2000
        - General (Box 412, Folder 6-13)
        - Report (Box 412, Folder 14)
      - Child Care and School-Age Programs
        - General, 2000-2001, n.d. (Box 413, Folder 1)
        - Contractors, 2000 (Box 413, Folder 2)
        - Responses by question (Box 413, Folder 3-9)
        - Responses by state
          - Maine-Massachusetts (Box 413, Folder 10-11)
          - Michigan-North Carolina (Box 414, Folder 1-5)
        - Telephone Follow-up Survey, 2001
          - General (Box 414, Folder 6)
          - Survey forms, California - Virginia (Box 414, Folder 7-9)
      - Use of Vans in Transporting Children, 1999 (Box 415, Folder 1)
      - "Working Women Count!," 1994, 1999 (Box 415, Folder 2)
    - Training
      - Miscellaneous training materials, 1970-99, n.d. (Box 415, Folder 3-5)
      - "Do You Know Your Community?" a beginning study course in what all citizens ought to know by Alice Standish Buell, circa 1922 (Box 415, Folder 6)
      - Pre-Convention Public Policy Event, 1982 (Box 415, Folder 7)
      - Public Policy Forum: To Promote Empowerment Through Public Policy, May 1990 (Box 415, Folder 8)
      - Workshop on Freedom and Its Responsibility, Oct 1956 (Box 415, Folder 9)
      - The YWCA and World Problems, Outline No. II, Mexico, 1927 (Box 415, Folder 10)
      - Public Policy and Advocacy Orientation, 1999 (Box 415, Folder 11)
      - YWCA Cares for Children Seminars
        - 8 Nov 2002 (Box 415, Folder 12)
        - 20 Nov 2002 (Box 415, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B. Program Subject Files
    - Civil liberties and democratic rights
      - American defense-civil defense, 1946-62 (Box 416, Folder 1)
      - Anti-lynching-mob violence, 1932-52 (Box 416, Folder 2-5)
      - Bible reading and prayers in the public schools, 1962-71, n.d. (Box 416, Folder 6-7)
      - Campus unrest
        - General, 1965-69 (Box 416, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence in response to National Board Action, 1970-71 (Box 416, Folder 9-10)
        - Killings at Southern University, 1972-73 (Box 416, Folder 11)
      - Capital punishment, 1958-76 (Box 416, Folder 12)
      - Civil liberties
        - General
          - 1935-43 (Box 416, Folder 13-14)
          - 1944-76 (Box 417, Folder 1-9)
        - Civil Liberties Group (Public Affairs Committee), 1939-48 (Box 417, Folder 10-12)
      - Civil rights, President's Commission on, 1946-60 (Box 417, Folder 13)
      - Communism
        - General, 1924-58, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 1-4)
        - Reference materials (Box 418, Folder 5)
        - Behind the Lace Curtains: YWCA response, 1948-49 (Box 418, Folder 6)
        - House Un-American Activities Committee, 1945-63 (Box 418, Folder 7-10)
        - Loyalty issue
          - General
            - 1947-Sep 1950 (Box 418, Folder 11-13)
            - Oct 1950-70 (Box 419, Folder 1-3)
          - Dies Committee, 1939-43 (Box 419, Folder 4)
          - Internal Security Act, 1950, 1971 (Box 419, Folder 5)
          - Repeal of Emergency Detention Act, 1970-71 (Box 419, Folder 6)
        - YWCA Panel on Communism, 1947 (Box 419, Folder 7)
      - Conscription
        - Compulsory military training and selective service, 1926-46 (Box 419, Folder 8-10)
        - Conscientious objectors, 1940-70 (Box 419, Folder 11-12)
        - Conscription of women, 1941-44 (Box 419, Folder 13-15)
        - YMCA-YWCA Ad Hoc Committee on "War Affected Persons," 1972-74 (Box 420, Folder 1-2)
      - Criminal Justice Codification, Revision, and Reform, 1972-76 (Box 420, Folder 3)
      - Fascism: List of typical organizations, 1934-40 (Box 420, Folder 4)
      - Franchise
        - Armed forces, 1942-44 (Box 420, Folder 5)
        - District of Columbia residents, 1959-75 (Box 420, Folder 6-7)
      - Freedom programs
        - General, 1936-63, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 8-11)
        - Freedom Agenda Program of the Carrie Chapman Catt Memorial Fund, 1954-59 (Box 420, Folder 12-13)
        - Fund for The Republic grant to YWCA, 1955-57 (Box 421, Folder 1)
        - Library project with National Council of Jewish Women, United Church Women, and National Council of Negro Women, 1954-55 (Box 421, Folder 2-3)
        - Speak Up for Freedom with National Council of Jewish Women, 1952-54 (Box 421, Folder 4)
      - Gun control, 1967-98 (Box 421, Folder 5-11)
      - Hawaii-Alaska statehood, 1946-59 (Box 421, Folder 12-14)
      - Poll tax, 1939-51 (Box 422, Folder 1-4)
      - Racism: Angela Davis Case
        - General, 1970-72 (Box 422, Folder 5)
        - YWCA Statement of Concern, 1970 (Box 422, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1970-72 (Box 422, Folder 7-9)
        - Ad-hoc Committee on the Open Letter to YWCAs, 1971 (Box 422, Folder 10)
        - Advisory Committee on the trial and the YWCA position, 1971-72 (Box 422, Folder 11)
      - Sex discrimination: Title IX, 1972-81 (Box 422, Folder 12-13)
      - Sexual orientation
        - General, 1973-92 (Box 422, Folder 14)
        - Conference Call, 1995 (Box 422, Folder 15)
        - NOW Lesbian Rights Resources Kit, 1993 (Box 422, Folder 16)
    - Education
      - Beverly Hills Tri-Y Club project, 1940 (Box 423, Folder 1)
      - Education for citizenship, 1922-50 (Box 423, Folder 2)
      - Federal aid to education
        - General, 1933-71 (Box 423, Folder 3-16)
        - Higher education legislation, 1957, 1965 (Box 424, Folder 1)
        - Chronologies, 1940-54 (Box 424, Folder 2)
        - Public aid to private/parochial schools, 1938-72 (Box 424, Folder 3)
      - National Board support for a U.S. Department of Education, 1922-39 (Box 424, Folder 4)
      - Postal rules for educational material, 1953-58 (Box 424, Folder 5)
      - Reference materials, 1944-50, n.d. (Box 424, Folder 6)
    - Ethnic Groups
      - General, 1945, 1972-95 (Box 424, Folder 7)
      - African Americans
        - Affirmative action: The Bakke case, 1976-78 (Box 424, Folder 8)
        - Civil rights and race relations, 1932-67, 1996-97 (Box 424, Folder 9-16)
        - Economic opportunities, 1933-41 (Box 425, Folder 1-2)
        - Fair Employment Practices Commission
          - General, 1940-54 (Box 425, Folder 3-11)
          - Summary of National Board Actions, circa 1952 (Box 425, Folder 12)
        - Race discrimination in the armed forces
          - General, 1940-53, n.d. (Box 426, Folder 1-3)
          - ACLU Conference Against Discrimination in the War Effort, 1943-44 (Box 426, Folder 4)
          - National Public Affairs Committee Actions and Education towards elimination of race discrimination in the war effort, 1940-42 (Box 426, Folder 5)
        - Race relations and the YWCA
          - General, 1920-63 (Box 426, Folder 6-9)